Andre Young

17102 Ashton CT Accokeek MD, 20607

Cell: (202) 369-8494 • andrejyoung@gmail.com • https://andreyoung.dev • https://github.com/youngaj

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineering Manager with over 20 years of development experience and a commitment to delivering quality solutions that exceed expectations. Looking for a position that will utilize my strengths and experiences while allowing me to grow and learn new techniques and skills both technical and professional.

SKILLS

React	AWS Certified	Git
Gatsby / NextJS / CRA	RESTful Services	Continuous integration
AngularJS	GraphQL	Docker
Node.js	ASP.NET & ASP.NET Core	Agile Project Management
JavaScript / TypeScript	C#	Mentorship
HTML	VB.NET	Community building
CSS	Automated Testing	Requirements gathering

EDUCATION

Architecting with AWS Greenbelt, MD

https://aws.amazon.com/training/course-descriptions/architect/

University of Maryland College Park, MD

Major: Computer Science (Software design and Programming) Degree: **Bachelors of Computer Science**, December 2002

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Exploration & Space Communications (ESC) Public Website

- Lead a team of developers, system administrator and designer to implement a design created in XD with a tight delivery date and limited specifications. Designed a deployment and management system for the content managers to preview their changes and deploy on demand to dev, staging and/or production environments.
 - Client/UI Created using Gatsby with Material-UI components. This stack was chosen for the front end to enhance SEO, faster load times and to support lower bandwidth devices.
 - CMS Strapi was chosen as CMS layer by a previous developer and was approved by management. At the
 time of implementation this product was in a Beta release which proved to be a complication but one that we
 worked around.
 - Server The project required the ability to send emails. ASP.NET Core was chosen to provide the server layer given the experience level of the system administrator that would be providing support
 - Orchestration layer This layer is written in NodeJS due to its flexible nature and easy integration with other command line tools (Gatsby, .NET Core, etc) needed to orchestrate the building and deployment to various environments.

ANDRE YOUNG 2/5

Symphony

• Designed and implemented a web application to organize, share, and secure project files. This application also tracked frequently asked questions (FAQs), software inventory, hardware inventory, employee onboarding, and much more. This application was created and maintained using SCRUM principles with two week iterations. The core application components consist of the following:

- Client/UI Angular 1.x SPA for the client using a mixture of factories, directives, components and routes based on the best practices found in the Angular 1 Style Guide.
- Web API –The Web API layer, written in C#, handle requests from the client, coordinating various services to produce a response.
- Services, Repositories, and Entities These services house the core business logic, data access and data entities.
- Background Service This service handles long running and/or background tasks such as change tracking and cache invalidation, etc. via the Service and Repositories DLLs mentioned earlier.
- Technologies: SQL Server 2016, Redis, Neo4j, Visual Studio 2019, ASP.NET 4.7.2 (Web API), JavaScript, Angular 1.x, Node.js, and various JavaScript libraries and NuGet Packages.

FLEX

- Designed and implemented a web application to automate and assist financial/resource analysis (RAs) for Space Science Mission Operations (SSMO) of the Astrophysics Projects Division of NASA. This tool provides a consistent way for the RAs to pull and organize financial data. This project saves hundreds of hours of manual effort each month on the part of the RA team and allows them to spend more time analysing the data.
 - Client/UI Angular 1.x SPA for the client using a mixture of factories, directives, components and routes based on the best practices found in the Angular 1 Style Guide.
 - Web API –The Web API layer, written in C#, handle requests from the client, coordinating various services to produce a response.
 - Services, Repositories, and Entities These services house the core business logic, data access and data entities.
- Technologies: SQL Server 2012, Visual Studio 2019, ASP.NET 4.5.x (Web API), JavaScript, Angular 1.x, various JavaScript libraries and NuGet Packages.

Goddard Review Management System (GRMS 3.0)

- Designed and implemented an internet based application to track project review Request for Action (RFA). This application is designed with three tiers for optimum security and portability.
- The User Interface (UI) employs a user centric design, designed to be intuitive and responsive. AJAX components give instant feedback.
- The Business Logic Layer (BLL) contains object oriented classes that organize all related functionality and encapsulate the majority of the requirements. The BLL also contains notable non-requirement objects such as the application log object which captures system errors and reports them to the programmer and the button object which allows system administrators to create new functionality through the user interface.
- The Data Access Layer (DAL) manages all access to the SQL Server 2008 database. Each object has a stored procedure that manages the searching, adding, deleting, loading and other functionality.
- Technologies: SQL Server 2008, Visual Studio 2008, ASP.NET 3.5, AJAX toolkit, jQuery

Requirements Mapping Database

- Designed and implemented an internet based application to principally track requirements throughout the life cycle of
 application development. This application also tracks inter relationships between all the principal objects of a web
 application which include but are not limited to the initial user requirements, code objects and functions, database
 tables and fields, user interface pages, and system bugs.
- The back end of this system is powered by a SQL Server 2008 database which employs numerous tables that represent the various objects and their relationships. Each principle object is managed by an intricate stored procedure designed to manage the various functionalities required by the application including adding, editing, deleting, searching, and creating dynamic links to other principle objects
- Technologies: SQL Server 2008, Visual Studio 2008, ASP.NET 3.5, AJAX toolkit

ANDRE YOUNG 3/5

 Tailor large scale Document Configuration Management systems to meet the changing requirements of NASA's Global Precipitation Measurement (GPM) project, Landsat Data Continuity Mission (LDCM) project and Stinger Technologies (SGT)

- Configure web and database servers along with several COTS programs to work harmoniously with NGIN
- Correct numerous bugs in legacy code and create code enhancements such as multiple document editing pages to make the application user-friendly and increase efficiency.
- Take the lead in finding ways to make code modular and scalable for future implementations and additions.
- Provide system administrative support and training to GPM, LDCM as well as LUNAR projects.
- Technologies: Classic ASP, SQL Server 2005-2012, Visual Studio, ASP.NET 2.0

Digital Math Library (DML)

- Designed and implemented a system to share new mathematical theorems and ideas in an effort to increase collaboration and discussion between parties in remote locations of the world.
- Designed an Entity-Relationship Diagram that incorporated the requirements of the customer and the interface development group.
- Lead a team of five developers in developing a multi-table database using MySQL along with wrapper functions written in Java and SQL to access and translate data into a useful format.
- Assisted in writing documentation for application including the first and second draft of the requirements document, the specification document, and the help files.
- Technologies: Unix, GDB Debugger, Java, SQL, MySQL

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineering Manager Digital Focus TECH Supervisor: Justin Bachorik
April 2020 – current Capital One

Hours/week: 40

Lead development effort for Capital One project. This responsibility includes providing technical mentorship to the
development team, planning and collaborating with senior management, application architecture and exploring new
technologies for feasibility.

 IT Manager & Lead Developer
 Code 450, 444, 480, & 301
 Supervisor: Colleen Ponton

 July 2012 – April 2020
 NASA: ASRC Federal
 301-286-4428

Hours/week: 40-45

- Lead development effort for PAAC IV Contract. This responsibility includes providing technical mentorship to the
 development team, planning and collaborating with senior management, application architecture and exploring new
 technologies for feasibility.
- Lead development effort for Exploration & Space Communications (ESC), Satellite Servicing Projects Division (SSPD) and Space Science Mission Operations (SSMO) support applications. This effort includes maintaining, enhancing and managing the migration of legacy applications. This position also encompases architecting and implementing new applications using the latest technology and proven design principles.
- Initiated and led an internal <u>developer group meetup</u> to share and leverage individual knowledge and skills across multiple contracts and Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC). The group is also designed to tackle common problems such as redundancy and lack of communication between individual in-house applications.

Senior Application DeveloperCode 301 & 700Supervisor: Rob Swartz / Richie WeisJuly 2011 – July 2012NASA: ASRC PRIMUS301-286-6770 / 301-286-4428

Hours/week: 40

- Upgrade and maintain Code 301's Goddard Review Management System (GRMS 3.0) that tracks Requests for Action (RFA) from the various reviews on and off center.
- Analyze and design the next generation configuration management tool (MIS 2.0) to incorporate coding best practices, object oriented design, N-tier application layering, as well as the flexibility to handle the previous 18 different variations of the MIS 1.0 versions in a single code base and database while maintaining the ability for each instance to have individual traits, functionality and processes.

ANDRE YOUNG 4/5

• Support Student On-Line Application for Recruiting Interns, Fellows, and Scholars (SOLAR) an online application used by all NASA centers to allow students to apply for, and be selected for internships, fellowships and scholarships using a SQLServer 2000 database and ColdFusion 8 front end.

MIS V (Senior Programmer) LRO & Code 301 Supervisor: Richie Weiss

July 2007 – July 2011 NASA: ASRC Federal 301-286-4428

Hours/week: 40

• Upgraded and maintained Code 301's previous Goddard Review Management System (GRMS 2.0) that tracked Requests for Action (RFA) from the various reviews on and off center.

- Researched, designed and built the next generation Goddard Review Management System (GRMS 3.0) that employs
 modern design principles and tools such as Object Oriented code design, ASP.NET 3.5, AJAX Controls, SQL Server
 2008, and other 3rd party tools.
- Manage project milestones and two other employees to maintain workflow and project deadlines.
- Created and maintained software requirement and development tracking and traceability tool which enable both
 programmers and clients to find exactly where requirements are met throughout the application. This tool also
 provides a wealth of information during and after development that greatly increases efficiency and adaptability of the
 software it traces by tracking numerous inter relationships between code, database objects, user interface,
 requirements, etc.
- Tailor large scale ASP application (NGIN) that provides Action Items, Configuration Management, Drawings, Shared Files, etc. to meet the requirements of NASA's Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO) project.

Software Engineer Peace Corps Project Supervisor: Barbara Schipper

May 2007 - July 2007 Systems Management Engineering Inc. 703-525-7500

Hours/week: 40

- Implement modules for Peace Corps' Volunteer Information Database Application Project (VIDA) to transition from MS Access to a .Net 2.0 Winforms application. (MS SQL, ADO.Net, Data Dynamics ActiveReports, Infragistics NetAdvantage)
- Create Active Reports using VB.NET.
- Worked with team members to solve complex problems such as offline data synchronization.

MIS III (Programmer) GPM & LDCM & LRO Supervisor: Fred Brooks

February 2006 – May 2007 NASA: SGT Inc. 301-286-4428

Hours/week: 40

- Tailor large scale Active Server Page (ASP) application (NGIN) that provides Action Items, Configuration
 Management, Drawings, and Shared Files along with numerous other modules to meet the requirements of NASA's
 Global Precipitation Measurement Project, Landsat Data Continuity Mission (LDCM) and LUNAR project.
- Debug and rewrite pages that are not working correctly.
- Add new features to simplify and shorten current procedures.
- Manage SQL Server Database for 5 NGIN systems with over 163 tables, 136 Views, and 47 stored procedures each.
- Lead and participated in group discussions to standardize NGIN Development in an effort to make the NGIN product portable and scalable.
- Implement changes to code and server in response to and to prevent security threats such as SQL Injection Attacks.

ASP Programmer GPM & LDCM Supervisor: Fred Brooks

April 2005 – February 2006 NASA: **PRISM Inc.** 301-286-4428

Hours/week: 40

- Tailor large scale ASP application (NGIN) that provides Action Items, Configuration Management, Risk
 Management, Drawings, Shared Files, and numerous similar modules to meet the requirements of NASA's Global
 Precipitation Measurement Project, Landsat Data Continuity Mission (LDCM) and LUNAR project.
- Debug and rewrite pages that are not working correctly.
- Add new features to simplify and shorten current procedures.
- Provide user administrator duties.

ANDRE YOUNG 5/5

 Programmer
 Office of Multi-Media Services
 Supervisor: Jeffrey Hammer

January 2003 – April 2005 Dept. of State: **Viatech Inc.** 202-647-7781

Hours/week: 40

• Designed and coded an online application to order, track and manage certificates using ASP, SQL Server and JavaScript.

- Test and provide feedback on current and upcoming Viatech applications.
- Provide and research new ideas for applications.

Researched and planned for the creation of an office wide system that will track new jobs, estimate job costs, track
user time spent on each job, along with materials to gather true cost of each job.

Document Specialist Office of Multi-Media Services Supervisor: Jeffrey Hammer

May 2002 – January 2003 Dept. of State: **Viatech Inc.** 202-647-7781

Hours/week: 40

Created layouts and posters using Photoshop7.0, Illustrator 10.0, and PageMaker7.0.

- Maintained Multi-Media Services supply stock using a Microsoft Excel spreadsheet application that I created.
- Light PC trouble shooting for the Customer Service branch of Multimedia office

Student Intern Office of Multi-Media Services Supervisor: Phyllis Smith

June 1999 – May 2002 Department of State 202-647-1105

Hours/week: 40

- Set up a database using MS Access along with an intranet web site to request certificates.
- Set up a database using MS Access to organize and track printing jobs.
- Light PC trouble shooting for the Customer Service branch of the Multimedia Office.
- Created publication layouts using PageMaker 6.5 and Photoshop 5.0.

HONORS & AWARDS

2018 Flight Projects Directorate Peer Award:

- <u>June 2018:</u> **Special Act Team** "For your valuable contributions to the success of the Flight Projects Directorate, you have been selected as a 2018 Peer Award recipient."
- June 2018: Excellence as Mentor "Under Your Wing "For your extraordinary concern and drive to ensure peers, mentees and the community have the tools necessary to succeed.

Certificate of Appreciation

- <u>December 2014</u>: "In recognition of your continuous efforts to encourage the software developers within the Goddard Space Flight Center to work collaboratively. Through your bi-weekly meetings where developers share their code, tools, and best practices, a new positive culture of learning has flourished."
- December 2014: "In recognition of your contribution and support as a Mentor and participating in the PAAC II Mentorship Program"
- August 2003: "In recognition of your outstanding achievement in support of the US Department of State Multi-Media Services"
- May 2002: "We value very sincerely your dedicated service."

RHG Exceptional Achievement for Engineering Team

• "For dedication and teamwork leading up to the launch of the Raven Technology Module to the International Space Station."

Franklin Award

- February 2002: "In recognition of your contributions to the success of the Chile Declassification Project"
- August 2000: "For dedicated performance that has led to improved customer relations."

REFERENCES

Available upon request